<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>howto on lijqhs&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://lijqhs.github.io/categories/howto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in howto on lijqhs&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lijqhs.github.io/categories/howto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>更新Github博客主题设置踩的坑</title>
      <link>https://lijqhs.github.io/2022/03/pitfalls-in-updating-blog-theme-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lijqhs.github.io/2022/03/pitfalls-in-updating-blog-theme-settings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GitHub is not only a cool community for developers who can create teams, share code, and even make friends, but it also provides free tools for people who like to toss around ideas. &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/en/free-pro-team@latest/github/working-with-github-pages/about-github-pages#about-github-pages&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; is such a fancy service where you can easily setup your own websites by just a few mouse clicks. Companies and project teams can easily create product homepages on it, and individuals who like to document things and share ideas can also easily build blogs on it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Change The Theme of A Hugo Blog</title>
      <link>https://lijqhs.github.io/2020/11/how-to-change-the-theme-of-a-hugo-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 23:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lijqhs.github.io/2020/11/how-to-change-the-theme-of-a-hugo-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago I &lt;a href=&#34;https://lijqhs.github.io/2020/11/how-to-setup-a-blog-with-hugo-and-github-pages-on-mac/&#34;&gt;migrated this blog&lt;/a&gt; to Hugo from Jekyll and employed a beautiful theme called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/olOwOlo/hugo-theme-even&#34;&gt;Even&lt;/a&gt;, a concise and powerful hugo theme, which fascinated me so much until I came across another graceful and exquisite hugo theme called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kakawait/hugo-tranquilpeak-theme&#34;&gt;Tranquilpeak&lt;/a&gt;, brought by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kakawait&#34;&gt;Thibaud Lepretre&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/LouisBarranqueiro/hexo-theme-tranquilpeak&#34;&gt;original hexo theme&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I decided to change the theme of this blog and I took the following steps to accomplished that, which was very easy and worth a share here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Setup a Blog with Hugo and Github Pages on Mac</title>
      <link>https://lijqhs.github.io/2020/11/how-to-setup-a-blog-with-hugo-and-github-pages-on-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 23:19:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lijqhs.github.io/2020/11/how-to-setup-a-blog-with-hugo-and-github-pages-on-mac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GitHub is not only a cool community for developers who can create teams, share code, and even make friends, but it also provides free tools for people who like to toss around ideas. &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/en/free-pro-team@latest/github/working-with-github-pages/about-github-pages#about-github-pages&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; is such a fancy service where you can easily setup your own websites by just a few mouse clicks. Companies and project teams can easily create product homepages on it, and individuals who like to document things and share ideas can also easily build blogs on it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git快速指南</title>
      <link>https://lijqhs.github.io/2019/03/git-quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 18:45:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lijqhs.github.io/2019/03/git-quickstart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;很多公司内部使用GitLab来做版本管理，假设你已经按照公司wiki设置好了Git账户。那么如何快速开始使用Git进行代码版本管理，下面是一些常用流程步骤。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install and Configure Elasticsearch Clusters</title>
      <link>https://lijqhs.github.io/2018/08/how-to-install-and-configure-elasticsearch-clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 21:45:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lijqhs.github.io/2018/08/how-to-install-and-configure-elasticsearch-clusters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Elasticsearch is a highly scalable open-source full-text search and analytics engine based on Lucene. This post focus on how to setup an Elasticsearch cluster. I have three Linux servers to build an Elasticsearch cluster. I referred to many materials on the web to get a clear configuration on how to setup an Elasticsearch cluster but many articles were too old with a lot of outdated parameters. The best reference is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/elasticsearch/reference/current/setup.html&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; on official website of Elasticsearch. Here I will get you a concise and informative reference. Following these steps the cluster will be easily setup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Create Virtual Environments by venv</title>
      <link>https://lijqhs.github.io/2018/08/how-to-create-virtual-environments-by-venv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 20:11:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lijqhs.github.io/2018/08/how-to-create-virtual-environments-by-venv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I tested examples of the book &lt;strong&gt;Deep learning from scratch&lt;/strong&gt;, a RuntimeError prompted told me matplotlib backend was not able to function correctly as my Python is not installed as a framework. The error message guided me to the Matplotlib FAQ (&lt;a href=&#34;https://matplotlib.org/faq/osx_framework.html&#34;&gt;Working with Matplotlib on OSX — Matplotlib 2.2.3 documentation&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The page shows &lt;code&gt;virtualenv&lt;/code&gt; is to blame as the virtualenv creates a non framework build even if created from a framework build of Python. To solve the problem the best and the simplest way is to use the build-in virtual environment tool &lt;code&gt;venv&lt;/code&gt; provided since Python 3.4.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Properly Install Python3 and Virtualenv on Mac</title>
      <link>https://lijqhs.github.io/2018/08/how-to-properly-install-python3-and-virtualenv-on-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 19:01:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lijqhs.github.io/2018/08/how-to-properly-install-python3-and-virtualenv-on-mac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I got a Macbook Pro, the first thing I thought was how to deploy a developing environment for programming and data analysis on Mac OS. I decided to install Python3 althought macOS comes out with a native python environment Python 2.7.10. The best way I found on the Internet is from the page of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.davidculley.com/installing-python-on-a-mac/&#34;&gt;David Culley&lt;/a&gt; where he gives several alternatives to set up a Python3 working environment. The post of &lt;a href=&#34;https://stringpiggy.hpd.io/mac-osx-python3-dual-install/&#34;&gt;Candy Tsai&lt;/a&gt; also helps a lot. The easiest method is might to use Anaconda a integral distribution for python which is popular for scientific computing. I like to install necessary packages for myself so I choose the Homebrew way. &lt;a href=&#34;https://brew.sh/&#34;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt; is called the missing package manager for macOS and it is a hot word if you search on the Internet for softwares installation on macOS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
